JESSICA CLAIRE

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000.

Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

-

8

• :

A

::

P

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'd like to build upon my 15+ years of digital content and communication strategy & consulting experience in a new and challenging role. What I do well, is: writing/editing targeted messaging for web, blogs and print; enforcing brand $marketing/tone/style; \ nurturing \ community \ engagement; \ creating \ \& \ executing \ social$ media strategy; researching & reporting competitive intelligence; leading events & projects. I'm known for communicating complex topics effectively, managing meaningful relationships, delivering & reporting results and resolving issues quickly -all while maintaining a good attitude and sense of humor.

CORF **QUALIFICATIONS**

- Focused on clients & exper
- Driven to deliver results
- Solves issues & problems
- Generates creative ideas
- Challenges traditional think
- Proficient with current technology

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota Minneapolis, MN • 1992 – â

Bachelor of Arts: Mass Communications - GPA:

Get Satisfaction 2012 – –

Certificate: Certified Community Manager -GPA:

, • – –

: - GPA: College of Liberal Arts Dean's List

EXPERIENCE

Lee Enterprises, Incorporated - Sr. Manager, Digital Content & Social Media Team Missoula, MT, · · 03/2012 - Current

- Lead team of digital content and social media managers responsible for executing company's digital and social strategy. Developed digital content ${\mathfrak A}$ social strategy for member and shopper websites:
- MyPrime.com and PrimeHelps.com
- Created web style guide incorporating company's "Let's Be Clear" writing principles for the web
- Influential key member of website redesign team which includes: participating in design sessions, & developer grooming/backlog sessions, influencing requirements, utilizing wires, creating copy decks, authoring, producing and publishing content.
- Strategize with leaders in marketing, creative and customer experience teams to ensure design/brand/tone/experience is integrated and consistent across all
- Author all content in Spanish
- Use current web tools: Adobe Experience Manager, Adobe Analytics, Hootsuite, JIRA, Confluence, Service Now

Facebook - Managing Editor

Irvine, CA, • • 2009 - 02/2012

- Manage strategy for campus content and online campus community comprised of 37,000 students, faculty, alumni and prospects.
- Focused on connections, engagement between peers, faculty and alumni, networking, sharing expertise and knowledge.
- Collaborate with business partners from across the company including: marketing, Corporate Communications/PR, legal, UX, developers, interactive design and production teams, to deliver relevant content, simplified navigation of website, improved overall user experience-resulting in increased traffic to website and content.
- Editor for all campus news including managing editorial calendars, writing and editing copy, basic production for image news stories, student news blog, content feeds, faculty news blog, program news pages and employee news.
- Develop and curate relevant content tailored to specific programs and audiences in support of successful academic learning, including; news copy, video, blogs posts, RSS feeds, images, content feeds, discussions and communities of practice,
- Write and enforce guidelines for effective and safe participation in university wide discussions: moderate discussions, track abuse, escalate issues and communicate effectively and appropriately.
- Moderate discussions and content for 26 individual academic, professional groups and honor societies, aligning with each group's goals/mission/vision.
- ${\it Manage \ campus \ content \ including \ copy, \ news, \ images, \ documents, \ video, \ blogs,}$ RSS, subscriptions, discussion feeds, links, etc.
- Write and edit copy for Web, mobile and print copy.
- Co-lead content strategy for faculty website redesign
- Work includes: audit, evaluation, review, writing/editing, governance and intake process.
- Co-manage social media strategy for company with team, utilizing multiple messaging and networking channels including: Facebook, Linkedin, Twitter, Google+, YouTube, Pinterest, in an effort to engage with prospects, students, alumni and in an effort to gain brand advocates.
- Listen, measure, track and report social engagement, growth and trends using Adobe Omniture, Radian6 (Salesforce), Facebook Insights, Google Analytics and
- Provide competitive analysis on Capella's campus technology, community and mobile capabilities utilizing UX testing, vendors and research studies (Communispace and NIIT).
- Use and knowledge of: CRM (Peoplesoft), CMS (Liferay and Wordpress), VersionOne (Agile methodology), Sharepoint, HTML (basic), Dreamweaver (basic), Basecamp, MS Office Suite.

- results: 314,381 1:1 friend relationships 139,784 discussion posts 19,383 updated university profiles 21,162 chat sessions 30+ academic groups, professional and honor societies Co-led content strategy process for redesign of faculty website, including: content audit, evaluation, review with content owners, editing/rewrite, working with UX team to position/structure content in a meaningful, easily navigable way.
- Member of social media strategy team for company, including how to use various channels to reach different audiences and deliver appropriate messaging through each: Facebook pages, Linkedin groups/pages, Twitter account, YouTube Channel, Google + and Pinterest pages.
- Publish social media scorecard and quarterly update to leaders and stakeholders on state of community progress related to company initiatives and department goals.
- Measure/track and report on the success of campus community using Omniture, Liferay, Google analytics.

Ameriprise Financial, Inc. - Senior Consultant, Corporate Communications City, STATE, • • 2006 - 2008

- to RiverSource Asset Management marketing and RiverSource distribution businesses on communication strategies: developing marketing communications plans, determining audiences, developing appropriate voice/tone/messaging/brand/style and delivering through appropriate channels.
- Wrote and edited funds marketing communications news for internal company portal and external funds product site.
- Communications lead on major business initiatives: RiverSource Web 2.0 and Certificate Co.
- · project.
- · Developed process and editorial calendar for Evergreen stories.
- Edited content and presentations for internal communications consultants and Community Relations department.
- · Led weekly RiverSource internal communications/media relations team meetings.

RiverSource Distributors Ameriprise Financial - Communications Manager City, STATE, • • 1999 - 2006

- Developed annual communication strategy for large wholesaling organization comprising 350 people.
- · Aligned communication strategy with sales goals.
- Determined key audiences, appropriate messaging/tone/style and distribution channels, timing and measures for success.
- Wrote and edited copy for leaders, wholesalers, conference team, marketing partners and financial advisors.
- Implemented new communications branding process for wholesaling organization as part of the sixth largest spin-off in U.S.
- history (from American Express to Ameriprise Financial, Inc.).
- Editor of Wholesaler Essentials, a weekly online sales news update for wholesalers.
- Editor of Premier Magazine, a quarterly financial magazine for top producing Ameriprise financial advisors.
- Led product distribution town hall for senior vice president and wholesalers of the insurance company.
- Managed the first-ever American Express Due Diligence Meeting in San Diego, CA, for 200 top producing funds and annuities financial advisors.
 Planned and executed the first Funds Investment Symposium satellite broadcast
- from Minneapolis to six major cities, nationwide.

 Managed budget, selected vendors, negotiated pricing and production costs for
- Coordinated six corresponding events nationwide including presenters and
- Coordinated six corresponding events nationwide including presenters and program for each host city.
- Managed exclusive Premier Clubs recognition and reward club for top producing advisors of funds, annuities and insurance products.
- Wrote and edited content for GVP Summit welcome packets, and hosted welcome event.
- Led new advisor tours among three organizations.
- Wrote script and toured hundreds of new advisors through wholesaling organization, investment department and central call center to demonstrate our business.

American Express - Colleges and Conferences Coordinator

City, STATE, • • 1997 - 1999

- Planned and managed insurance, investment and small business colleges for select advisors.
- Included calling advisors, managing lists, setting up classes, working at the marketplace with business partners and delivering following up materials.
- Created presentations, produced course materials, managed logistics, coordinated marketplace for Region Vice President Group, for national conferences in Tampa, Long Beach, Orlando, and San Francisco.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Minnesota Interactive Marketing Association (MIMA)
International Association of Business Communicators (IABC)

INTERESTS

- Field Middle School PTA Board Member 2013-present
- Founder and leader Field Middle School Grants Team 2013-present
- Together for Good, Capella fall campaign
- 2012 Project Homeless Connect volunteer
- 2008-2010 Chair from IABC MN to Minnesota Council of Nonprofits, 2008 Habitat for Humanity Ameriprise Financial,
- 2004, 2006-2007 American Express Champions Council
- Habitat for Humanity, 2005 Jacob's Well (church), South Minneapolis launch team and leader 2006-2012

Tech: Adobe Experience Manager (CQ5), Liferay, Adobe Analytics (Site Catalyst, Omniture), JIRA, VersionOne, Confluence, Oracle (CRM), Adobe Dreamweaver, Wordpress, Tumblr, Basic HTML, Basecamp,

Social: Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest, Facebook, Google+, Linkedin

Microsoft Office Suite: Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook, Visio, Publisher, Sharepoint)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Awards

- Blackboard Exemplary Online Course award winner (team) 2012
 Paragon Division Award, Ameriprise Financial, 2006 Volunteer -